In the scenario we saw earlier in this section with Noah and Aaliyah,
we saw them come together to meet for the first time to discuss the transformation.
What could Noah have done differently?
Luckily, Noah did pivot in the meeting to ask Aaliyah how she was handling everything.
Because actually, one way of really demonstrating empathy is asking about other people —
not making assumptions about how they’re feeling or thinking about something,
and actually just giving them the time and space to explain how they feel, or what they think.
And Noah listened in that moment. He really did.
And it was the beginning of building a bridge in his relationship with Aaliyah —
a constructive relationship, so that they can work happily
together throughout the rest of the project.
Now, what did Aaliyah do in that meeting that demonstrated empathy?
She naturally came in with her own agenda.
She was the one who had set the meeting. However, she did ask Noah early on:
“Is there anything else you’d like to talk about?”
And she created a bit of space there to ensure that there was time for Noah to express what might be on his mind,
and that she would be in a position to be able to address some of it.
Little steps like that can go a long way to demonstrate empathy in a business context.